Hyunyoung Kim

Gwangju, S. Korea

+82 10 5050 0720

hyuny.kim@chonnam.ac.kr

http://hyunyoungkim.com

USER RESEARCH/PHYSICAL INTERACTION SPECIALIST

Leverages interdisciplinary expertise on software/hardware/UX design to make meaningful human-computer interaction methods. Bachelor in computer science, experience in robotics club and Samsung strengthened 5 years of practical research experience, and enabled 7 publications and 6 patents. Master's thesis regards gestural interface on keyboard using IR-proximity sensors to accelerate command input and reduce the burden of command remembrance.

Education	
KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology), Daejon, South Korea Master of Science, Digital Media Program, Advisor: Minsoo Hahn, GPA: 3.27/4.3	Feb 2009 – Feb 2011
Sungkyunkwan University, Suwon, South Korea Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering, GPA: 3.93/4.5	Mar 2004 –Feb 2009
Park University, MO, USA Transferred student	Jan 2007 – May 2007
Professional Experience	
Chonnam National University, Gwangju, South Korea Research Assistant, Human-Computer Interaction	Nov 2014 – Current
Association for Vertical Farming, Munich, Germany Web Designer/Developer	Dec 2013 – May 2014
Samsung Electronics, Suwon, South Korea UX Designer, User Research & UI Design, UX Center, DMC Research Centers	Feb 2011 – May 2013
Samsung Software Membership, Seoul, South Korea Student Researcher, Interaction Design & Prototyping	Jan 2010 – Dec 2010
KOREA MART, Japan Intern, Homepage & shopping mall development	Jan 2006 – Feb 2006
Honors and Awards	
Employee of Month, Samsung Electronics, 3 times	2011 – 2013
Korea National Robot Soccer Mirosot League, 3rd place, Korea Robot Soccer Association	Aug 2005 Feb 2005
Champions League MiroSot Small League, 1st place, Kangnam University Korea National scholarship, KAIST	2009 – 2010
Four-years full scholarship based on Korean national scholastic achievement test (1st grade/4%), Sungkyunkwan University	2004 – 2008

Publications

Hyunyoung Kim, Jinsul Kim, A Study on Design and Needs of New Wearable Devices Using a Design Methodology, Proceedings of the 17th KKITS Spring Conference, Gwangju, South Korea, 2015 (Korean)

Sanghyun Park, Jisu Kim, **Hyunyoung Kim**, Jinsul Kim, Research on the Smart Wheelchair for User Stability Based on an Infrared Sensor, Proceedings of the 17th KKITS Spring Conference, Gwangju, South Korea, 2015 (Best Paper Award) (Korean)

Hyunyoung Kim, Changhee Cho, Jisu Kim, Sanghyun Park, Jinsul Kim, Kuinam J. Kim, Localizing a Flying Object on Target Place Using Heterogeneous Binary Sensors, ICMWT, Bangkok, Thailand, 2015

Hyunyoung Kim, Ilmin Kim, Jinsul Kim, Designing the Smart Foot Mat and Its Applications: as a User Identification Sensor for Smart Home Scenarios, The 6th 2015 International Interdisciplinary Workshop Series, HSST, Jeju, South Korea, 2015

Sanghyun Park, **Hyunyoung Kim**, Jinsul Kim, Taeksoo Ji, Myoung Jin Lee, A Novel Detection Method Integrating Hybrid Sensors for Motorized Wheelchairs, ICISA, Pattaya, Thailand, 2015

Hyunyoung Kim, Gesture-Recognition Interface with Keyboard Embedded IR Modules, <u>Master's Thesis '11</u> (Korean, Short description in English)

Hyunyoung Kim, Kuenhwan Kwak, Jongwoo Jung, Insik Myung, Minsoo Hahn, Tablaction: collaborative brainstorming system with stylus-fingertip interactions on tablet PCs, <u>VRCAI '10</u>

Hyunyoung Kim, Donghoon Lee, Jeehyung Lee, Personalized Comment Spam Filtering Using Clustering, KIIS '08 (Korean, Short description in English)

Patents

Hyun-Young Kim, Hee-Won Jung, Device and method for transmitting electronic key thereof, US20140115493 A1

Hyun-Young Kim, Tae-hwan WI, Method and device for transmitting information related to event, US20140075329 A1

Hyun-Young Kim, Tae-hwan WI, User terminal device and system for performing user customized health management, and methods thereof, US20130268292 A1

Sung-Jin Park, **Hyun-Young Kim**, User terminal, external apparatus, data transceiving system, and data transceiving method, US20140128031 A1

Eun-young Lim, **Hyun-Young Kim**, Yeon-hee ROH, Joo-kyung Woo, Young-shil Jang, User terminal device for providing electronic shopping service and methods thereof, US20130332228 A1

Jae-Woo Ko, Tae-hwan WI, Hee-Won Jung, **Hyun-Young Kim**, Bo-seok MOON, Management server and method for controlling device, user terminal apparatus and method for controlling device, and user terminal apparatus and control method thereof, US20130268998 A1

Projects

Smart Textile as Wearable and 3D Interfaces

Exploring the capability of smart textiles as novel interfaces. Ideation,

Chonnam National University Nov 2014 – Current implementation, managing cooperative students.

Tools: Teensy, C#, Unity3D

Projectile detection on a target board

Implementing a shooting target scoring system using computer vision. Managing project and implementing.

Tools: C++, OpenCV

Chonnam National University Nov 2014 – Current

Research Proposal for Korean National Research Foundation: Research on Heterogeneous Smart Wearable Devices Based Personal Sensor Cloud Technology

Cooperative research proposal among three universities – CNU, StonyBrook, SUNY Korea. Outlined the proposal in Korean style, wrote CNU part, organized meetings

Chonnam National University Apr 2015 – Jul 2015

Vertical Farming Website

Website visual design and implementation for non-profit organization in Germany

Association for Vertical Farming
Dec 2013 – Apr 2014

Samsung Smart Home

Smart Home service & UI design. Part of the mobile and TV interfaces demonstrated at '13 IFA. The UX, harmonizing 3rd party products and worldwide users was designed strategically based on the global user research and usability test.

Samsung Electronics Oct 2012 – May 2013

Smart LED

Sub-project of Smart Home. Managed project, defined requirements by discussing marketing specialists and engineers, and designed UX.

Samsung Electronics Feb 2013 – May 2013

Mobile Ads & Commerce

Samsung Wallet. Demonstrated at MWC '13. Designed UIs for merchants' part, managed card reader appressory design, led user research.

Samsung Electronics Apri 2012 – Sep 2012

Patenting Task Force

Researching on the emerging technology, finding new business opportunities and patenting on related ideas. Consulting ideation process and developing patents with patent specialists and engineers. Related patents are pending.

Samsung Electronics Dec 2011 – Apr 2012

Medical Device & Service Design

Performed a medical device design with IDEO and new business development division; Learned IDEO's research know-how in paired observation, interview, and observational sharing.

Samsung Electronics Aug 2011 – Nov 2011

Medical & Health service Patenting Task Force

A TF patenting technologies and services regarding new medical and health services for Samsung's medical business opportunity. Organized TF, researched background technologies and patented an idea.

Samsung Electronics Apr 2011 – Jul 2011

Master's Thesis

On-keyboard gesture recognition system using IR-proximity sensors. Designed interaction methods and gestures, implemented the system.

Tools: Arduino, C#

Dec 2009 – Dec 2010

KAIST

Digi-log Show Control System

Integrated show control system with physical & on-screen interfaces Tools: WPF

Korea National University of Arts Apr 2010 – Dec 2010

Jon-Ro Man-Machine Interface

Quality Assurance

Jong-ro Science Jul 2009 – Oct 2009

Bachelor's Thesis

A personalized comment spam filtering, based on a hypothesis that criteria for spam are different among people. Generated ideas, implemented the system, collected data for comments.

Sungkyunkwan University May 2008 – Nov 2008

Tool: Python

Other Research Experience

A pressure sensitive tablet and its practical uses, software implementation

2010

2010

Yo! Run! – Mobile running assistant system using foot sensor and mobile application, user research and software implementation

A remote music-controlling tumbler, implementation with Arduino and Processing

2009

Skills

General Skills Creative and analytical thinking, communication skills

Languages & APIs C++, C#, Matlab, Java, WPF, C, Vuforia, HTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQL, Windows Mobile,

Google Map API, Jess

Development Tools Visual Studio, Processing, Unity3D, Eclipse IDE, XCode

User Research Usability test, task observation, survey design and analysis, ideation moderation, heuristic

analysis, home visiting, user interview, GOMS, wizard of oz

UX Design Scenarios, use cases, personas, wireframe, user flow, Axure, Omnigraffle, Balsamiq, Flowella

Visual Design Illustrator, Photoshop

Engineering Arduino, EagleCAD, circuit design, artwork

Teaching and Service

TA	C++ instruction for Bachelors	2015
Mentor	Women's science thesis competition for undergraduates and high school students	2011
Instructor	Designing circuits, basics from soldering to implementing, for undergraduate lab interns	2010
Instructor	Trends of human sensing technology, in course seminar	2008

Language Education

Rheinland Privatschule, Essen, Germany Sep 2013 – Oct 2013

German Language Course

HLI Liberty, MO, USA Sep 2006 – Dec 2006

English Language Course

Language Skills

English Spoken and written proficiency in English (IELTS 7.5/ TOEFL 96/ TOEIC 935)

German Basic grammatical and conversational knowledge of German

Korean Native

References

 Minsoo Hahn
 Professor, KAIST
 mshahn2@kaist.ac.kr

 Jinsul Kim
 Associate Professor, Chonnam National University
 jsworld@chonnam.ac.kr

 Sung Park
 Expert UX Consultant, SK Telecom
 spica7601@partner.sk.com

 Change of Virgon Accident UX Decisions Support Floature in Consultant UX Decisions S

Changwon Kim Assistant UX Designer, Samsung Electronics changwon1.kim@samsung.com